<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>News Lancashire</title><description>Lancashire&apos;s premier local news source. Breaking news, politics, sport, crime and community stories.</description><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/</link><language>en-gb</language><item><title>Two men arrested after alleged racially aggravated assault in Accrington town centre</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/two-men-arrested-after-alleged-racially-aggravated-assault-in-accrington-town-ce/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/two-men-arrested-after-alleged-racially-aggravated-assault-in-accrington-town-ce/</guid><description>Two men are in custody following an alleged racially aggravated assault in Accrington town centre. The incident has prompted local police to increase patrols in the area as enquiries continue. Residents and shoppers in the Hyndburn town centre can expect to see a heightened officer presence while the investigation proceeds.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:28:10 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>&apos;We&apos;re just really happy&apos;: family reacts to news elderly relative&apos;s Lancashire care home will remain open</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/we-re-just-really-happy-family-reacts-to-news-elderly-relative-s-lancashire-care/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/we-re-just-really-happy-family-reacts-to-news-elderly-relative-s-lancashire-care/</guid><description>Relatives of elderly residents have expressed relief after Lancashire County Council confirmed its care homes will not close. Community campaigners successfully fought plans to shut the facilities, securing a future for vulnerable local people. The decision allows residents to continue receiving care in their established homes near family and friends.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:17:29 GMT</pubDate><category>community</category></item><item><title>More than £100,000 cash and drugs seized after van stopped on M6 in Lancashire</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/more-than-100-000-cash-and-drugs-seized-after-van-stopped-on-m6-in-lancashire/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/more-than-100-000-cash-and-drugs-seized-after-van-stopped-on-m6-in-lancashire/</guid><description>Police seized over £100,000 in cash and illegal drugs during a stop at a Lancashire motorway service station. The operation on the M6 highlights ongoing efforts to intercept criminal activity traveling through the county&apos;s road network. Motorists using local services may notice increased patrols as authorities target drug trafficking routes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:16:02 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>Accrington driver more than three times drink-drive limit after breakdown on M6</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/accrington-driver-more-than-three-times-drink-drive-limit-after-breakdown-on-m6/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/accrington-driver-more-than-three-times-drink-drive-limit-after-breakdown-on-m6/</guid><description>An Accrington motorist was arrested after breaking down on the M6 and calling for assistance multiple times. Officers discovered the driver was over three times the legal alcohol limit when they responded to the stranded vehicle. The incident serves as a warning to Lancashire road users about the dangers and legal consequences of drink-driving on the county&apos;s motorways.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:06:12 GMT</pubDate><category>transport</category></item><item><title>Woman pushed from van and dragged along Preston street as police hunt wanted man who may be in Burnley</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/woman-pushed-from-van-and-dragged-along-preston-street-as-police-hunt-wanted-man/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/woman-pushed-from-van-and-dragged-along-preston-street-as-police-hunt-wanted-man/</guid><description>Police are searching for a suspect following a disturbing incident in Preston where a woman was pushed from a van and dragged along the road. The victim was holding onto the vehicle when she was forced out in the Lancashire city. Detectives believe the wanted man may have fled to Burnley, and are appealing for local information to locate him.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:59:35 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>Lancashire Crime Statistics: 2025-12</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/lancashire-crime-statistics-2025-12/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/lancashire-crime-statistics-2025-12/</guid><description>Latest figures reveal 457 crimes were reported across Lancashire during December 2025, with violent offences accounting for the largest category at 189 incidents. Burglaries totalled 46 cases whilst shoplifting and public order offences reached 34 and 30 respectively. The data, which lacks specific location breakdowns, provides a countywide snapshot of policing challenges facing local communities.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:57:00 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>Oliver Ryan MP: What steps she is taking to reduce dangerous journeys for unaccompanied child refugees with family in the UK.</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/oliver-ryan-mp-what-steps-she-is-taking-to-reduce-dangerous-journeys-for-unaccom/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/oliver-ryan-mp-what-steps-she-is-taking-to-reduce-dangerous-journeys-for-unaccom/</guid><description>Burnley MP Oliver Ryan has challenged ministers to improve protections for child refugees travelling alone to reach relatives in Britain. The Lancashire parliamentarian seeks concrete measures to eliminate perilous crossings. The issue affects families across the county awaiting reunification.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:56:54 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Oliver Ryan MP: If she will make a statement on her departmental responsibilities.</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/oliver-ryan-mp-if-she-will-make-a-statement-on-her-departmental-responsibilities/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/oliver-ryan-mp-if-she-will-make-a-statement-on-her-departmental-responsibilities/</guid><description>Burnley MP Oliver Ryan has formally asked a government minister to outline her current departmental responsibilities in a parliamentary question. The request demonstrates ongoing scrutiny of government functions affecting East Lancashire residents.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:56:54 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Oliver Ryan MP: What recent steps she has taken to reduce the level of knife crime.</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/oliver-ryan-mp-what-recent-steps-she-has-taken-to-reduce-the-level-of-knife-crim/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/oliver-ryan-mp-what-recent-steps-she-has-taken-to-reduce-the-level-of-knife-crim/</guid><description>Burnley MP Oliver Ryan has pressed the government for details on recent measures implemented to reduce knife crime. The inquiry seeks clarity on how national strategies will address community safety concerns across Lancashire.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:56:54 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>King Charles III visit to Clitheroe: What you need to know including road closures and travel advice</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/king-charles-iii-visit-to-clitheroe-what-you-need-to-know-including-road-closure/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/king-charles-iii-visit-to-clitheroe-what-you-need-to-know-including-road-closure/</guid><description>Royal visit arrangements are underway in Clitheroe as King Charles III prepares to tour the Ribble Valley town. Road closures and safety protocols will disrupt traffic through the centre, requiring residents to plan alternative travel routes. The engagement brings national attention to the local community.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:55:25 GMT</pubDate><category>transport</category></item><item><title>Every Michelin Guide restaurant in Lancashire ahead of 2026 ceremony next week</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/every-michelin-guide-restaurant-in-lancashire-ahead-of-2026-ceremony-next-week/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/every-michelin-guide-restaurant-in-lancashire-ahead-of-2026-ceremony-next-week/</guid><description>Lancashire&apos;s culinary reputation faces scrutiny as the county&apos;s Michelin Guide entries are highlighted ahead of next week&apos;s 2026 ceremony. Local diners can anticipate which restaurants may receive prestigious stars or Bib Gourmand awards.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:52:25 GMT</pubDate><category>business</category></item><item><title>Plans to revive and develop Golden Ball pub in Lancashire village take big step forward</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/plans-to-revive-and-develop-golden-ball-pub-in-lancashire-village-take-big-step-/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/plans-to-revive-and-develop-golden-ball-pub-in-lancashire-village-take-big-step-/</guid><description>Restoration plans for the derelict Golden Ball pub in Over Wyre have advanced significantly, offering hope for the village landmark&apos;s revival. The proposals aim to return the historic building to active community use after years of neglect. Local residents anticipate further details on the development timeline.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:51:07 GMT</pubDate><category>health</category></item><item><title>A tough window for Preston - Heckingbottom</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/a-tough-window-for-preston-heckingbottom/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/a-tough-window-for-preston-heckingbottom/</guid><description>Preston North End manager Paul Heckingbottom has described the club&apos;s January transfer dealings as chaotic during the window&apos;s final hours. The Deepdale side faced a challenging conclusion to the month as they reshaped their squad. Lancashire supporters will be monitoring how these late changes impact the team&apos;s Championship campaign.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:32:59 GMT</pubDate><category>sport</category></item><item><title>Tragedy as teenage Preston student found dead in University of Lancashire campus halls of residence</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/tragedy-as-teenage-preston-student-found-dead-in-university-of-lancashire-campus/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/tragedy-as-teenage-preston-student-found-dead-in-university-of-lancashire-campus/</guid><description>A teenage student has been found deceased in her accommodation at the University of Central Lancashire&apos;s Preston campus. Lancashire Police were called to the university halls following the discovery, though authorities have indicated there are no suspicious circumstances surrounding the death. The university is offering support services to students and staff affected by the tragedy.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:05:43 GMT</pubDate><category>education</category></item><item><title>Just to say there are two names we should think of right now: 1) Virginia Giuffre, who not only spoke out about Epstein...</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/just-to-say-there-are-two-names-we-should-think-of-right-now-1-virginia-giuffre-/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/just-to-say-there-are-two-names-we-should-think-of-right-now-1-virginia-giuffre-/</guid><description>Rights advocates are recognising Virginia Giuffre and journalist Julie K Brown for their pivotal roles in exposing the Epstein abuse scandal. Their work in amplifying survivor voices and pursuing accountability continues to resonate with justice campaigners across Lancashire communities.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:03:44 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>51 brilliant pictures snapped in Preston more than 40 years ago in 1983 bringing the era vividly back to life</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/51-brilliant-pictures-snapped-in-preston-more-than-40-years-ago-in-1983-bringing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/51-brilliant-pictures-snapped-in-preston-more-than-40-years-ago-in-1983-bringing/</guid><description>A collection of 51 photographs documents Preston during 1983, capturing the city&apos;s industrial heritage and street scenes over four decades ago. The images provide Lancashire residents with a visual record of daily life and architectural landscapes from that era. Local historians value the archive for preserving the area&apos;s social history and community character.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:00:39 GMT</pubDate><category>community</category></item><item><title>25 atmospheric photos that bring Blackpool’s late 1980s vividly back to life</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/25-atmospheric-photos-that-bring-blackpool-s-late-1980s-vividly-back-to-life/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/25-atmospheric-photos-that-bring-blackpool-s-late-1980s-vividly-back-to-life/</guid><description>A new photography collection captures Blackpool&apos;s seaside atmosphere during the late 1980s. The images document the resort&apos;s iconic promenade and attractions during a pivotal decade for the Lancashire coastal town.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:00:25 GMT</pubDate><category>general</category></item><item><title>&apos;I tucked my children into bed - then woke up to carnage after my tumble dryer caught fire in Cleveleys&apos;</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/i-tucked-my-children-into-bed-then-woke-up-to-carnage-after-my-tumble-dryer-caug/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/i-tucked-my-children-into-bed-then-woke-up-to-carnage-after-my-tumble-dryer-caug/</guid><description>A mother and her four-year-old daughter were rendered unconscious following an overnight tumble dryer fire at their Cleveleys flat. The blaze destroyed the family home and required emergency rescue services to evacuate the unconscious victims. Lancashire Fire and Rescue Service is reminding households to check appliance safety following the serious incident.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:00:04 GMT</pubDate><category>general</category></item><item><title>13 pics as Jason Manford hosts padel session with Blackpool school kids</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/13-pics-as-jason-manford-hosts-padel-session-with-blackpool-school-kids/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/13-pics-as-jason-manford-hosts-padel-session-with-blackpool-school-kids/</guid><description>Comedian Jason Manford visited Blackpool to introduce local schoolchildren to padel tennis during a special coaching session. The event gave pupils the chance to try the growing racquet sport with the television personality. Photographs captured the youngsters participating in the activities alongside the Lancashire-born entertainer.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:55:48 GMT</pubDate><category>education</category></item><item><title>Former police officer who worked in Burnley during his career jailed after admitting coercive and controlling behaviour towards a woman</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/former-police-officer-who-worked-in-burnley-during-his-career-jailed-after-admit/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/former-police-officer-who-worked-in-burnley-during-his-career-jailed-after-admit/</guid><description>A former police officer who served in Burnley has been imprisoned after pleading guilty to charges of coercive and controlling behaviour against a woman. The defendant appeared at court for sentencing earlier this week following an investigation into the domestic abuse offences. Lancashire residents have reacted with concern to the case involving a former member of the county&apos;s police force.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:54:26 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>Update on strategic review of our in-house adult social care services.</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/update-on-strategic-review-of-our-in-house-adult-social-care-services/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/update-on-strategic-review-of-our-in-house-adult-social-care-services/</guid><description>Lancashire County Council has issued an update regarding its examination of internally managed adult social care provisions. The strategic review assesses how services support vulnerable adults throughout the county. Changes to care delivery may follow as the council evaluates current operations against future community needs.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:43:07 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>CCTV captures Lancashire mosque burglar taking his shoes off before stealing charity box</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/cctv-captures-lancashire-mosque-burglar-taking-his-shoes-off-before-stealing-cha/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/cctv-captures-lancashire-mosque-burglar-taking-his-shoes-off-before-stealing-cha/</guid><description>CCTV footage has captured a burglar removing his shoes before stealing a charity box from a Lancashire mosque. The theft of funds intended for humanitarian causes has caused distress within the local religious community. Police are seeking information to identify the suspect shown respecting the building&apos;s customs while committing the offence.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:39:31 GMT</pubDate><category>community</category></item><item><title>LCCA marks one year anniversary</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/lcca-marks-one-year-anniversary/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/lcca-marks-one-year-anniversary/</guid><description>A key Lancashire County Council initiative has completed its first year of operation across the county. The milestone marks twelve months of service delivery since the programme&apos;s launch. Residents continue to engage with the scheme as it moves into its second year of supporting local communities.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:33:07 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Reform’s Matthew Goodwin’s big idea would punish millions of women and strip them of their basic dignity to choose.    E...</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/reform-s-matthew-goodwin-s-big-idea-would-punish-millions-of-women-and-strip-the/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/reform-s-matthew-goodwin-s-big-idea-would-punish-millions-of-women-and-strip-the/</guid><description>Reform UK figure Matthew Goodwin has proposed controversial policy changes affecting women&apos;s rights, drawing criticism from political opponents. Party leader Nigel Farage has reportedly backed the proposals, sparking debate across Lancashire about the party&apos;s stance on social issues. The plans have prompted concerns among local campaigners about potential impacts on healthcare access and personal freedoms.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:31:18 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Morecambe Winter Gardens announces weekend of events for Eric Morecambe 100 year celebration</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/morecambe-winter-gardens-announces-weekend-of-events-for-eric-morecambe-100-year/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/morecambe-winter-gardens-announces-weekend-of-events-for-eric-morecambe-100-year/</guid><description>Morecambe Winter Gardens Theatre will host a special weekend of events celebrating the centenary of Eric Morecambe, the comedian born in the Lancashire seaside town. The festivities form part of a year-long programme honouring the local entertainment legend&apos;s legacy.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:18:51 GMT</pubDate><category>community</category></item><item><title>Rapist who attacked woman in Burnley jailed for 23 years</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/rapist-who-attacked-woman-in-burnley-jailed-for-23-years/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/rapist-who-attacked-woman-in-burnley-jailed-for-23-years/</guid><description>A 41-year-old man has been sentenced to 23 years in prison for raping a woman in Burnley. The lengthy custodial term reflects the gravity of the attack committed within the Lancashire town. Local residents will view the conviction as a significant measure toward ensuring community safety and delivering justice.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:17:00 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>I’ve hit the ground running for 2026 by asking 10 questions in Parliament throughout January, taking the issues and conc...</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/i-ve-hit-the-ground-running-for-2026-by-asking-10-questions-in-parliament-throug/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/i-ve-hit-the-ground-running-for-2026-by-asking-10-questions-in-parliament-throug/</guid><description>The Member of Parliament for Blackpool has tabled ten parliamentary questions throughout January, raising constituents&apos; concerns directly with government ministers. The MP stated the initiative aims to secure additional support and resources for the seaside town from Whitehall departments. The questions covered issues affecting local residents and the coastal community&apos;s specific needs.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:06:50 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Plans to transform Grade II listed Shrine Church in Blackpool into therapy centre for health unit</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/plans-to-transform-grade-ii-listed-shrine-church-in-blackpool-into-therapy-centr/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/plans-to-transform-grade-ii-listed-shrine-church-in-blackpool-into-therapy-centr/</guid><description>Plans to convert Blackpool&apos;s Grade II-listed Shrine Church into a mental health therapy centre are awaiting planning approval. The landmark building would provide NHS treatment facilities while preserving its historic architecture. The proposal aims to balance heritage conservation with addressing urgent healthcare needs for Lancashire residents.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:02:47 GMT</pubDate><category>health</category></item><item><title>42 flashback Burnley bar photos from 2014 featuring Mojitos, Remedy and more</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/42-flashback-burnley-bar-photos-from-2014-featuring-mojitos-remedy-and-more/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/42-flashback-burnley-bar-photos-from-2014-featuring-mojitos-remedy-and-more/</guid><description>A collection of 42 archive photographs capturing Burnley&apos;s nightlife scene from 2014 has been published, featuring images from venues including Mojitos and Remedy. The gallery offers local residents a look back at the town&apos;s social venues from over a decade ago.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:00:01 GMT</pubDate><category>general</category></item><item><title>Update after arrests made connected to devastating fatal Wigan Road crash</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/update-after-arrests-made-connected-to-devastating-fatal-wigan-road-crash/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/update-after-arrests-made-connected-to-devastating-fatal-wigan-road-crash/</guid><description>Four people arrested following a fatal collision on Wigan Road that claimed four lives have been released on bail pending further enquiries. The devastating crash has sent shockwaves through the local community, with residents calling for improved road safety measures along the route. Lancashire Police continue to investigate the circumstances surrounding the incident.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:59:00 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>Livingstone staying with Lancs three more years</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/livingstone-staying-with-lancs-three-more-years/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/livingstone-staying-with-lancs-three-more-years/</guid><description>Cricketer Liam Livingstone has committed to Lancashire County Cricket Club for the next three T20 Blast seasons. The England international&apos;s contract extension secures his presence at Old Trafford through 2027, bolstering the club&apos;s white-ball squad.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:57:16 GMT</pubDate><category>general</category></item><item><title>15 of the most romantic restaurants in and around Preston for an unforgettable Valentine&apos;s Day date</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/15-of-the-most-romantic-restaurants-in-and-around-preston-for-an-unforgettable-v/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/15-of-the-most-romantic-restaurants-in-and-around-preston-for-an-unforgettable-v/</guid><description>Preston couples planning Valentine&apos;s Day celebrations have numerous dining options across the city and surrounding areas. Local restaurants are accepting bookings for the February 14th celebrations, offering Lancashire residents a range of venues for the occasion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:53:17 GMT</pubDate><category>business</category></item><item><title>Are you a small business in #Preston? Enter the Small Business Growth Award being run by HSBC UK.  You don’t have to be...</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/are-you-a-small-business-in-preston-enter-the-small-business-growth-award-being-/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/are-you-a-small-business-in-preston-enter-the-small-business-growth-award-being-/</guid><description>Small businesses based in Preston have until February 9, 2026, to enter the Small Business Growth Award sponsored by HSBC UK. Entries are accepted from all local enterprises regardless of banking arrangements. The competition offers Lancashire firms recognition and exposure through the business awards scheme.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:49:00 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Cyclist hit by car and knocked off bike at Leyland&apos;s &apos;Bobby the Iron Horse&apos; roundabout in Earnshaw Bridge</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/cyclist-hit-by-car-and-knocked-off-bike-at-leyland-s-bobby-the-iron-horse-rounda/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/cyclist-hit-by-car-and-knocked-off-bike-at-leyland-s-bobby-the-iron-horse-rounda/</guid><description>Emergency services attended the Earnshaw Bridge roundabout in Leyland last night after a car collided with a cyclist, knocking him from his bike. The incident at the locally known &apos;Bobby the Iron Horse&apos; junction prompted police response to the scene.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:37:06 GMT</pubDate><category>general</category></item><item><title>Violent rapist who brutally raped and assaulted  sex worker given 23-year sentence</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/violent-rapist-who-brutally-raped-and-assaulted-sex-worker-given-23-year-sentenc/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/violent-rapist-who-brutally-raped-and-assaulted-sex-worker-given-23-year-sentenc/</guid><description>A defendant has received a 23-year prison term for sexually assaulting a sex worker during a prolonged attack in Burnley. The incident, which lasted three and a half hours, prompted a major police investigation in the Lancashire town. The court imposed the lengthy sentence following a conviction for the violent crime.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:36:00 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>Women&apos;s hormone expert and best-selling author brings new tour to Lancaster</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/women-s-hormone-expert-and-best-selling-author-brings-new-tour-to-lancaster/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/women-s-hormone-expert-and-best-selling-author-brings-new-tour-to-lancaster/</guid><description>A best-selling author and hormone specialist will bring her theatre tour to Lancaster to address misconceptions about women&apos;s health. The event aims to provide evidence-based information to local audiences on hormonal wellbeing and medical myths.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:31:47 GMT</pubDate><category>community</category></item><item><title>Man who called police for help on M6 found to be &apos;three times drink-drive limit&apos;</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/man-who-called-police-for-help-on-m6-found-to-be-three-times-drink-drive-limit/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/man-who-called-police-for-help-on-m6-found-to-be-three-times-drink-drive-limit/</guid><description>An Accrington man who contacted police for assistance after breaking down on the M6 was arrested when officers discovered he was over the drink-drive limit. The driver tested at more than three times the legal alcohol limit, according to Lancashire Constabulary.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:30:17 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>15 of the most romantic restaurants in Blackpool and the Fylde coast for an unforgettable Valentine&apos;s Day date</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/15-of-the-most-romantic-restaurants-in-blackpool-and-the-fylde-coast-for-an-unfo/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/15-of-the-most-romantic-restaurants-in-blackpool-and-the-fylde-coast-for-an-unfo/</guid><description>Couples across Lancashire seeking Valentine&apos;s Day dining options can choose from fifteen recommended establishments along the Blackpool and Fylde coast. Local restaurants are now accepting reservations for the February 14th celebrations. The selection showcases the area&apos;s diverse culinary offerings for residents planning special occasions.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:23:45 GMT</pubDate><category>business</category></item><item><title>Major Eden Project Morecambe progress required ahead of planned 2028 opening amid new designs</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/major-eden-project-morecambe-progress-required-ahead-of-planned-2028-opening-ami/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/major-eden-project-morecambe-progress-required-ahead-of-planned-2028-opening-ami/</guid><description>The Eden Project Morecambe faces a tight timeline to meet its planned late 2028 opening following the introduction of revised designs. Developers must accelerate construction schedules to deliver the ambitious coastal attraction, which is expected to bring significant economic benefits and tourism to the Lancashire seaside town.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:00:05 GMT</pubDate><category>business</category></item><item><title>Planning application submitted to redevelop former restaurant Langroyd Hall in Colne into over-50s apartments</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/planning-application-submitted-to-redevelop-former-restaurant-langroyd-hall-in-c/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/planning-application-submitted-to-redevelop-former-restaurant-langroyd-hall-in-c/</guid><description>Developers have submitted plans to transform Langroyd Hall in Colne into residential apartments specifically designed for residents aged over 50. The proposal would see the former restaurant site converted to provide specialist housing in the Pendle area. Local planners will now review the application for the historic building&apos;s change of use.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:59:36 GMT</pubDate><category>business</category></item><item><title>We&apos;re celebrating 1 year and 5,000 members of Wandering Women with a silent disco walk</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/we-re-celebrating-1-year-and-5-000-members-of-wandering-women-with-a-silent-disc/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/we-re-celebrating-1-year-and-5-000-members-of-wandering-women-with-a-silent-disc/</guid><description>A Blackpool-based women&apos;s walking group marks its first anniversary this month, having grown to 5,000 members since its launch. The milestone will be celebrated with a silent disco promenade along the seafront, offering residents a unique community fitness event. The initiative highlights the growing popularity of social walking groups across the Fylde coast.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:56:01 GMT</pubDate><category>community</category></item><item><title>Lancashire sign ex-Australia captain Lanning for T20 Blast</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/lancashire-sign-ex-australia-captain-lanning-for-t20-blast/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/lancashire-sign-ex-australia-captain-lanning-for-t20-blast/</guid><description>Lancashire Cricket Club have signed former Australian captain Meg Lanning for the upcoming T20 Blast season. The world record holder will make her county debut with the team this summer, bringing vast international experience to Old Trafford.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:53:15 GMT</pubDate><category>sport</category></item><item><title>Wyre Council statement after teacher previously linked to Thornton theatre jailed over messages to child</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/wyre-council-statement-after-teacher-previously-linked-to-thornton-theatre-jaile/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/wyre-council-statement-after-teacher-previously-linked-to-thornton-theatre-jaile/</guid><description>Wyre Council and Cre8iv Little Theatre have responded after a piano teacher connected to the Thornton venue received a prison sentence for sending explicit messages to a 14-year-old student. Both organisations issued statements following the conviction concerning the safeguarding breach.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:47:08 GMT</pubDate><category>crime</category></item><item><title>Man found bleeding from head wounds after attack outside Preston Tesco last night</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/man-found-bleeding-from-head-wounds-after-attack-outside-preston-tesco-last-nigh/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/man-found-bleeding-from-head-wounds-after-attack-outside-preston-tesco-last-nigh/</guid><description>Police are investigating after a man suffered head injuries during an assault outside a Tesco supermarket in Preston yesterday evening. The victim was discovered bleeding at the scene and received medical attention. Authorities are appealing for witnesses to the incident in the city centre.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:31:50 GMT</pubDate><category>general</category></item><item><title>Go-ahead for £9.3m record swim projects</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/go-ahead-for-9-3m-record-swim-projects/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/go-ahead-for-9-3m-record-swim-projects/</guid><description>Fylde Council has approved a £9.3 million investment in swimming facilities, marking the largest leisure spending commitment in the authority&apos;s history. The record funding will support new or improved aquatic projects across the borough, promising upgraded amenities for local residents.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:28:49 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Hundreds of volunteers ready to dig in to help support dunes</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/hundreds-of-volunteers-ready-to-dig-in-to-help-support-dunes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/hundreds-of-volunteers-ready-to-dig-in-to-help-support-dunes/</guid><description>Hundreds of volunteers will gather at St Annes beach from February 10 to 12 to plant thousands of recycled Christmas trees. The dune restoration work aims to protect Lancashire&apos;s coastal communities from erosion and flooding while recycling festive waste.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:27:34 GMT</pubDate><category>community</category></item><item><title>Talking Newspaper stalwart Joy dies at 101</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/talking-newspaper-stalwart-joy-dies-at-101/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/talking-newspaper-stalwart-joy-dies-at-101/</guid><description>Tributes are being paid to Joy, founder of Blackpool&apos;s talking newspaper for visually impaired residents, following her death at 101. The service provides audio news to blind and partially sighted people across the Fylde coast. Her dedication ensured Lancashire&apos;s visually impaired community stayed informed for decades.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:25:25 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>St Peter&apos;s Centre in Burnley to be renovated</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/st-peter-s-centre-in-burnley-to-be-renovated/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/st-peter-s-centre-in-burnley-to-be-renovated/</guid><description>St Peter&apos;s Health Centre in Burnley is set to undergo renovation work. The improvements aim to upgrade the facility serving local residents. Details on the scope and timeline for the project are expected to be announced.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:24:46 GMT</pubDate><category>health</category></item><item><title>Recently, I reposted the same photo to congratulate the school on winning an award and the comment section is suddenly f...</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/recently-i-reposted-the-same-photo-to-congratulate-the-school-on-winning-an-awar/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/recently-i-reposted-the-same-photo-to-congratulate-the-school-on-winning-an-awar/</guid><description>Racist abuse has flooded the social media page of a Lancashire MP after they congratulated a local school on winning an award. The representative reposted a previous photo with pupils, prompting a barrage of hostile comments directed at the children. The incident highlights rising online toxicity affecting county schools and public figures.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:08:12 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item><item><title>A couple of years ago, I posted a photo of me with the children of a school in my constituency on Facebook, receiving no...</title><link>https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/a-couple-of-years-ago-i-posted-a-photo-of-me-with-the-children-of-a-school-in-my/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://newslancashire.co.uk/article/a-couple-of-years-ago-i-posted-a-photo-of-me-with-the-children-of-a-school-in-my/</guid><description>A Lancashire MP has highlighted changing online attitudes after revealing a constituency school visit photo initially received positive reactions on social media two years ago. The post, shared from a local school in the representative&apos;s patch, originally garnered supportive responses from residents. The comparison illustrates shifting discourse around community engagement in the county.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:08:12 GMT</pubDate><category>politics</category></item></channel></rss>